A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Committee on States and Social Structures, Record Group 3, Series 4 FA1484 FA1484
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Committee on States and Social Structures, Record Group 3, Series 4
1980-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
FA1484
5.72 Cubic Feet 13 letter-size document boxes.
Arrangement
The Social Science Research Council archives are arranged into three record groups distinguished by the date of their donation to the Archive Center. Accession 1 (Record Group 1) consists of the documents received by the Archive Center in 1990; Accession 2 (Record Group 2) was transferred to the Archive Center in 1994; Record Group 3 was transferred to the Archive Center in 2017-2018.
Within series the records are primarily arranged in original order.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Social Science Research Council records were donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 1990 and record transfers continue periodically. The records in this series were received in 2016-2017.
Biographical / Historical
The Social Science Research Council (SSRC) is a private, not-for-profit organization established in 1923 to advance research in the social sciences. The SSRC came into being through the initiatives of Wesley C. Mitchell and Charles E. Merriam, members of the American Political Science Association. Representatives of the American Economic Association, the American Sociological Society, the American Statistical Association, the American Historical Association and the American Psychological Association assisted Merriam and his associates in forming the SSRC. They invited the participation of other national associations in anthropology, history, and psychology, many of which designated representatives to the SSRC in the year following its incorporation on December 27, 1924.
To support its work, the SSRC turned not to the U.S. government, whose support seemed more appropriate for the natural sciences, but to private foundations. For the first fifty years, well over three-quarters of the SSRC's funding was provided by the Russell Sage Foundation, the Ford Foundation, the Carnegie Corporation, and two Rockefeller philanthropies, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial and the Rockefeller Foundation. By the 1970s, however, funds for some special projects were obtained from federal agencies.
Other Finding Aids
Other finding aids documenting Social Science Research Council records include:
FA021 Social Science Research Council records, Record Group 1 and Record Group 2 FA1196 Social Science Research Council records, Economics Intiative, RG 3, Series 1 FA1196 Social Science Research Council records, Economics Intiative, RG 3, Series 1 FA1481 Social Science Research Council records, East Asia/Indochina, RG 3, Series 2 FA1483 Social Science Research Council records, Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS), Record Group 3, Series 3
Scope and Contents
The Committee on States and Social Structures series includes project proposals, conference and workshop papers and proposals, meeting records, correspondence and other research materials.
- Committee on States and Social Structures, 1980-1990; 4
  - Journals and Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Economic Ideas Meeting, 1986 October (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Meeting, 1986 October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Economic Ideas - Papers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - CSSS - Committee members, Annual Report, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CSSS Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CSSS - Child Care, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Day-care Facilities and Services for Children Under the Age of Three in the European Community (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CSSS - Child Care (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CSSS - Child Care (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PT - NSF proposal (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - CSSS - War Settlement Meeting, 1986 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CSSS - Child Care (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Meeting Notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - CSSS - Child Care, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Child Care - France, Sweden (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - (U.K.) Thomas Loram Research Unit (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CSSS - Child Care policies-research (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Child Care - Germany, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Child Care, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Child Care - Notes (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Keynesian Manuscript (Originals) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Hall Manuscript (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Child Care - Notes (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - (France) CRESAS (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Child Care (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - EEC, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CENSIS - Italy, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Child Care (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CSSS - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - CSSS Fundraising Initiatives, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - CSSS Funding, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - CSSS Budget-Finance (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - CSSS Annual Report - Current, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - CSSS Annual Reports - Past, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bringing the State Back In, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bringing the State Back In, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
  - Bringing the State Back In, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Program Statements, Early Proposals, Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Committee Proposal - Comments, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Committee Announcement, Memos to Scholars, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - War Settlement - Politics and Society Papers, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - War Settlement - Politics and Society Papers, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - War Settlement Meeting Notes (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Meeting Notes (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - CSSS - Keynesianism - Rosanvallon Article Translation, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Keynesian Publication Meeting - Arrangements, 1986 October 10-11 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - CSSS Keynesian Meeting Minutes, 1986 October 10-11 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - CSSS - Keynesian Project Draft - Hall, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Peter Hall - Keynesian Publication - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Peter Hall - Keynesian Publication - Letter to Contributors, 1986 November (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Papers on Keynesian Theory - Notes (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Keynesian Meeting Agendas, 1986 October 10-11 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Politics of Industrial Development in Newly Industrialized Countries, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - CSSS Notes and Drafts for Newly Industrialized Countries (NICs) Proposal (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - CSSS - Newly Industrialized Countries Project Draft (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1988 November (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1988 May (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1988 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1985 April 29 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1986 November 8 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - NIC Proposal - Carnegie Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - CSSS Finances, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - CSSS Business, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - CSSS Meeting, 1989 Fall (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - CSSS Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - CSSS - Memos, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - CSSS - NICs Correspondence, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - CSSS - Review, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - CSSS - Newly Industrialized Countries Project, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - CSSS - Working Group Papers, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - CSSS - Bringing the State Back In, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - CSSS - Committee Appointments, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - CSSS -Network (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - CSSS - Guidelines for Submission of Proposals, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - CSSS - Newsletter, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - CSSS - Newsletter Budget, 1986-1990 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - SSRC Newsletter Mailing List, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - CSSS - Newsletter - Preliminary Plans, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Proposals, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - CSSS Mailing List (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - CSSS - May 9 Meeting Arrangements, 1987 May 9 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CSSS Agenda Notes, 1987 May 9 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - CSSS - YE Meeting Notes, 1987 May 9 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Prof. Weinberger - Keynesian, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - CSSS - TJ Meeting Notes, 1986 November 8 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - CSSS - Meeting Arrangements, 1986 November 8 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - CSSS - Grant Applications, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - CSSS - Small Grants Correspondence, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - CSSS - Hauslohner Proposal, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - CSSS - War Settlement Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - CSSS - War Settlement Meeting Arrangements, 1986 November (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - CSSS - War Settlement Projects - Early Versions, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - War Settlement Papers, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Keynesian Papers, 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 2-4)
  - CSSS - Memos, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - CSSS Meeting Arrangements, 1990 May 5 (Box 13, Folder 6)